Inventory of the Evans-McCan Group video tape
Hoover Institution Archives
Evans-McCan Group video tape
1988-1989
2000C10
Evans-McCan Group.
1 manuscript box (11 VHS videocassette tapes) (0.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives
Video recordings related to political conditions in the Soviet Union. Includes interviews with Soviet political leaders. All recordings are on VHS tapes.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2000.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
American film production company.
Scope and Content of Collection
Video recordings related to political conditions in the Soviet Union. Includes interviews with Soviet political leaders. All recordings are on VHS tapes.
Soviet Union--Politics and government--1985-1991.; Ukraine.; Videotapes.
- Video recordings of footage of the USSR cities: Leningrad, Moscow, Suzdal, and Vladimir, including street scenes, government buildings, and historic sites, December 1988 - January 1989, 3 VHS videocassettes. Includes items 1-10 (Tape 1-3)
  - Moscow and Suzdal, USSR, December 1988 - January 1989 (Item 1-4)
  - Vladimir and Leningrad, January 1989 (Item 5-8)
  - Leningrad, January 1989 (Item 9-10)
- Video recordings of footage of the former Soviet Union, October 1990, 8 VHS videocassettes. Includes items 1-28 (Tape 4-11)
  - First meeting of Democratic Russia, Leningrad, USSR (Item 1)
  - Interviews with participants of First Democratic Russia meeting (Item 2)
  - Leningrad city scenes (Item 3-4)
  - Interview with Konstantin Cheremnykh, Democratic Union (Item 5-6)
  - Leningrad city scenes (Item 7-8)
  - Interview with Iueiĭ Rybakov, Deputy, Leningrad City Council (Item 9)
  - Interview with Leonid Romankov, Deputy, Leningrad City Council (Item 10)
  - Peter and Paul Fortress, Leningrad City Council in Session (Item 10b)
  - Leningrad city scenes (Item 11)
  - Interviews with ordinary Soviet citizens (Item 12)
  - Odessa city scenes, including kindergarten program (Item 13)
  - Odessa city scenes (Item 14)
  - Interview with Israil' Reznichenko, Kiev Memorial (in Russian) (Item 15)
  - Interview with Deputy of Ukrainian Soviet (Item 17)
  - Interview with Andriĭ Kulikov, Deputy Editor of News from Ukraine (Item 18)
  - Kiev student hunger strike and camp. Interview with Valeriĭ Grishchuk, Deputy, USSR Supreme Soviet (Item 19)
  - Interview with Dr. Lev Dul'nev, economist (Item 20)
  - Green World campaign rally. Speech by Iuriĭ Scherbak, Deputy, USSR Supreme Soviet (Item 21)
  - Interview with Alekandr Savchenko, RUKH (Item 22)
  - Bykovnia, Stalin-era mass grave site (Item 23)
  - Interview with Popular Front leader (Item 24)
  - Interview with Aleksandr Ostal'skiĭ, Izvestia reporter (Item 25)
  - Scenes of meetings, Arbat (Item 26)
  - Interviews with Iuriĭ Ruzhov and Arkady Murashev, Deputies, USSR Congress of People's Deputies (Item 27-28)